In this video, we are going to install Hyperledger Besu on Linux.
First, we need to install the dependency of Java.
I'm using the command 'sudo apt install openjdk-jre-headless', to automatically install Java.
I'll be asked for the password for my Linux instance.
An alternative way to do this is to go to the download Java link that is part of the Documentation and download the appropriate version of Java.
Once you've done that, you can now download the Besu packaged binaries from the Documentation.
We are now going to speed up this next part, but I'm downloading and extracting the packaged binaries into a folder called Code, which we'll come back to in the next step.
Now open up the terminal.
The first thing I'm going to do is just make sure that I have the appropriate folder installed.
Now we're going to run the command 'bin/besu --help'.
Before we run that command, I'm going to ensure that we have Java installed by running the command 'java --version'.
Now we're going to change directory to Code and into the installed binaries.
And now we're going to run that command 'bin/besu --help'.
If we've installed Besu successfully, we'll get all the options and subcommands that we can run on Hyperledger Besu.
Congrats, we've confirmed we've installed on Linux.